herts.ac.uk 2019-12-17

# Online privacy policy | About us | University of Hertfordshire

  * Home
  * Online privacy policy

At the University of Hertfordshire we believe strongly in protecting our users' privacy. We will not wilfully disclose information about our users to any third party without first receiving the relevant user's consent. This Privacy Policy sets out the privacy practices for the services offered on any University of Hertfordshire ('the University') owned and/or operated websites ('the Website'). Some parts of our on-line systems and services and our collaborative agreements are operated on our behalf by third-party organisations. By submitting your personal information you are consenting to the University holding it, in accordance with this policy, and where necessary carrying out these services by providing the relevant information to such organisations.

This Privacy Policy may be updated from time-to-time. You should check this page regularly to ensure that you are happy with any changes.

## Cookies

When you visit the Website, the University may send your computer a "cookie", a small file that resides on your computer's hard drive and allows the University to determine return users of the Website and to review how a user uses a website in order to make it more useful by tailoring the services it offers to the way(s) in which a user accesses them. Each cookie is unique to you and it can be read by the server or your browser software. You can set your browser not to accept cookies, although you may not be able to access all of the features on the Website, or the site may operate less efficiently.

We may also use cookies to authenticate and record your acceptance to other applicable terms and conditions and also your acceptance to the handling of other information, including personal data that you may voluntarily provide from time-to-time.

Cookies cannot be executed as code or used to deliver a virus. Other servers cannot read them and personal information cannot be gathered from them. They are simply an identifier shared between you and us; we do not share them with anyone. A cookie does not give the University access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share.

Information about how to configure your browser to block cookies can be found at:

The cookies used on our site are listed below.

### Analytics cookies

We use these cookies to anonymously collect information about how visitors use our site. They are set when you first visit the site and deleted when you close the web browser. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form and send it back to Google, who collate the information into reports that help us develop our website. Blocking these cookies will not impact on your use of our site.

### Online registration and purchasing

These cookies are set when you apply online for a University services such as a job vacancy, accommodation or a course of study. They are also set when you purchase an item from our online store. These cookies are used to maintain the status of your application or purchase throughout the process. Disabling these cookies may mean that you are unable to complete an application or purchase online. They will expire when you close your web browser.

### Social Networking Buttons

Many of our web pages contain links to social networking sites that are provided by the sites themselves such as Facebook and Twitter. The scripts used to generate these buttons come from from third party websites and the third parties might be setting cookies, gathering usage information and setting their own cookies. Details of their privacy policies can be found here:

### Embedded Video

We will embed videos into our web pages, mostly from YouTube and Vimeo. These third parties might be gathering usage information and setting their own cookies. Details of their privacy policies can be found here:
